Dharaneish V C

dharaneishvc@gmail.com | +91 9976507707 | Bengaluru | @Q@ & ee/dharaneishvc | dharaneishvc.github.io/portfolio

PROFILE

Software Engineer with 1 year of experience as AI/ML, full-stack & C++ Developer seeking a long-time SDE1 role to leverage technical, problem-solving & interpersonal skills to add value to the organization while enhancing skills and advancing career.

EXPERIENCE

Amadeus Labs, Bengaluru

SDE 1 (full-stack & C++ backend Developer) Jul

July 2024 - current

- Part of R&D airline reservation team, Working on C++ backend, python, angular, REST API, cloud, linux
- Updated and enhanced an internal data monitoring tool using optimal data structures and algorithms

Amadeus Labs, Bengaluru

SDE Intern (AI/ML Developer)

Feb 2024 - July 2024

• Built an ML-based tool to optimize reservation booking performance and reduce app component's failure rate using various ML & data models, Python, AutoML, Explainable AI and SQL

Vivriti Capital, Chennai

SDE Summer Intern (Full Stack Developer)

July 2023 - Aug 2023

• Built a full-stack PDF reader tool to extract, process, and display cloud-stored PDFs with interactive features on a web interface, using Python, Java, ReactJS, and AWS

EDUCATION

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, Coimbatore BTech - Computer Science Engineering 8.65/10 (Distinction) 2020-24

CBSE, India Secondary/Grade 12 - AISSCE 94.2% (School 2nd rank) Apr 2020

CBSE, India Secondary/Grade 10 - AISSE 94.6% (School 3rd rank) Apr 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: C, C++, Python, Java (5
 hackerrank)
- Basics of Haskell, Scala, GoLang, R lang, ARM assembly language
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Angular, AWS Basics
- Operating Systems: Windows 10, 11, Linux Ubuntu 22.0
- **SQL**: MySQL, Oracle, NoSQL, MariaDB
- Data science, AI: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Time series, NLP, IR
- Big Data: Hadoop, MapReduce, Hive, Pig, MongoDB, Cassandra, HBase, Spark, Sqoop, MS Excel
- Core Computer Science: Operating System, Computer Networks, Automata Theory, Compiler Design
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Jira, Confluence, Trello, AWS, Jenkins, Star UML, MS Office, Figma

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- AroygaSathi: Healthcare App: Develop predictive models using various complex ML & DL techniques to predict the presence or risk of different diseases & Interpretable AI techniques based on various datasets
- ML-based Sentiment Analysis: hotel review analysis, using various ML & DL predictive models, NLP Techniques
- Wikipedia page view analysis: Analyzed time series trends, patterns & forecast Wikipedia page views using models like Moving, Exponential Average & ARIMA, seasonal ARIMA, Holt-Winters, Auto-ARIMA.
- Online Canteen management System: Developed a full stack website for canteen management using MongoDB, ReactJS to do all CRUD operations, password-protected login, table booking, cart, order
- College Placement cell management: full-stack web development project using OOPS Java backend SQL, ReactJS for placement cell.
- **Hospital management System**: Developed a modular C++ project for patient management with CRUD operations and password-protected login, using OOP concepts, file management, & data structures

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS

- Comparative Analysis of Deep Learning and Machine Learning Methods for Network Intrusion Detection
 - o ICCCNT Conference 2023 @ IIT Delhi, doi: /10.1109/ICCCNT56998.2023.10308108
- Enhanced Botnet Attack Detection using Machine Learning and Neural Networks
 - o ICICTS Conference 2024 @ Tribhuvan University, Nepal, doi: 10.1109/ICICT60155.2024.10544628